Ernest Joseph Nzallawahe

DETAILS

+255710663944 ernestjoju@gmail.com

PROFILE

I am a Computer Science graduate who is self-motivated and dedicated to producing a high-quality standard of service, disciplined and resourceful with an analytical approach to computer science and problem-solving. I am 24 years old. Focused and quick learner am experienced in software development and organizing data to make it useful to both technical and non-technical team members. I can work in both team environments as well as using own initiative

EXPERIENCE

Softnet Technologies LTD, Dar es Salaam, *Software Developer (Intern)*

September 2021-PRESENT

- Develop Systems
- Design System
- Maintains Systems
- Working closely with other developers, UX designers, business and systems

Singo Africa LTD, Dar es Salaam, Software Developer (Intern)

July 2020- August 2021

- Researching, designing, implementation and managing software programs
- Testing and evaluating new programs identifying areas for modification in existing program
- Writing and implementing efficient code
- Working closely with other developers, UX designers, business and systems

TTCL, Posta network administrator (Practical Training)

July 2019 - September 2019

- Configure network hardware such as servers, routers, and switches.
- Upgrade, repair, and maintain computer networks.
- Troubleshoot various network issues.

PROGRAMMING SKILLS

- JavaScript
- Java
- Visual Basic
- Working with API
- Front-end (Vue.js, Angular & React)
- Backend (Node.js)
- Spring Boot
- SQL
- Rapid Pro

DATABASES MANAGEMENT SYSTEMS

- Mysql
- Postgresql
- SQL Server
- Microsoft Access

DATA COLLECTION TOOLS & VISUALIZATION

- Excel
- KobotoolBox
- Data Studio

OTHER SKILLS

- Ability to Work in a Team and Multitask
- Communication Skills
- Knowledgeable in User
 Interface/ User Experience
- Rapid Pro technology
- PM2 process manager
- Git
- Networking & Administration

EDUCATION

University Of Dar Es Salaam, Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Nov 2018- Jul 2021

University Of Dar Es Salaam, Diploma in Computer Science

Oct 2016- Jul 2018

Kampala International University, Certificate in Information Technology

Nov 2015- July 2016

Ujenzi Secondary School, Ordinary Level

Jan 2011- Nov 2014

MEMBER

Y4C innovation Hub (Youth 4 Children)

REFEREES

Dr. Josiah Patrick Nombo

Lecturer at CoICT - UDSM +255 786 083 888 jpnombo@udsm.ac.tz

Elirehema Paul

Software Developer at Singo Africa LTD +255 716 087 522 <u>elireham@singo.africa</u>

Jane Mgone

Innovation Officer At UNICEF +255688033587 jmgone@unicef.org

- Linux Operating System
- Computer maintenance and repair

AWARDS

U-report second winner

 Hackathon was prepared by UNICEF to solve problems given using Rapid Pro technology. And i managed to give solution and take a second winner place

Research Week at University Of Dar Es Salaam.

 awarded for participant in Exhibition

LANGUAGES

- English
- Swahili